<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Achievements | Mohibul Alam</title>
    <link>https://mohibul75.github.io/achievements/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mohibul75.github.io/achievements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Achievements</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mohibul75.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Achievements</title>
      <link>https://mohibul75.github.io/achievements/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safeguarding at Workspace</title>
      <link>https://mohibul75.github.io/achievements/safe-guard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mohibul75.github.io/achievements/safe-guard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Safeguarding at workspace training is an important program that aims to promote a safe and healthy work environment for employees. It is designed to equip employees with the necessary knowledge and skills to identify and prevent workplace hazards and risks, and to ensure the safety of everyone in the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The training program held on Brain Station 23 is a comprehensive program that covers various aspects of workplace safety, including risk assessment, hazard identification, emergency response, and health and safety regulations. The program is conducted by experienced trainers who use a variety of teaching methods, including interactive sessions, case studies, and group discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the training, participants are taught about the different types of hazards that can exist in a workplace, such as physical, chemical, biological, and ergonomic hazards. They are also trained on how to recognize the signs and symptoms of potential hazards and how to take appropriate actions to prevent accidents or injuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program also emphasizes the importance of emergency response procedures, including first aid, evacuation, and fire safety. Participants learn how to respond quickly and effectively in the event of an emergency to minimize the risk of injury or damage to property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the training also focuses on health and safety regulations and how to comply with them. Participants are taught about their responsibilities as employees, as well as the responsibilities of their employers, in ensuring a safe work environment. They also learn about the consequences of non-compliance with health and safety regulations, including legal and financial penalties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the Safeguarding at Workspace training held on Brain Station 23 is an essential program that helps promote a culture of safety in the workplace. By providing employees with the knowledge and skills to identify and prevent hazards, the training helps create a safer and healthier workplace for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buet Cse Fest DevOps Hackathon 2022</title>
      <link>https://mohibul75.github.io/achievements/buet-cse-fest-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mohibul75.github.io/achievements/buet-cse-fest-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;DevOps Gurus&amp;rdquo; team achieved a remarkable accomplishment by securing the 2nd position in the DevOps category at the Buet Cse Fest 2022 Hackathon. The team members, Mohibul Alam, Syed Yusuf Ahmed and Mahdee Hasan, demonstrated excellent skills and worked tirelessly for 24 hours to solve all the challenges presented to them during the competition. The team enjoyed the overnight competition and gained valuable experience and knowledge. The team&amp;rsquo;s achievement was recognized by Dr. Mohammad Kaykobad, who presented them with the prize. Unfortunately, Yusuf was unable to attend the prize-giving ceremony. The team used various technologies and tools to build their project, including Angular for frontend, Node js for backend, Docker and Docker Hub for containerization, Kubernetes for orchestration, Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) for infrastructure, Terraform and Github for infrastructure provision, Grafana and Promethus for infrastructure monitoring, Github Actions for CI/CD pipeline, and Hugo for documentation. The team expresses their gratitude to Rafed Muhammad Yasir for his guidance and continuous support, and they hope to become future champions in upcoming competitions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Certified Solution Architect- Associate(AWS SAA C-03)</title>
      <link>https://mohibul75.github.io/achievements/aws-saac-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mohibul75.github.io/achievements/aws-saac-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am proud to announce that I have successfully achieved the AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate certification. This certification is offered by Amazon Web Services (AWS) and validates my proficiency in designing and deploying scalable and reliable applications on the AWS platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate, I have demonstrated my expertise in designing resilient, high-performing, secure, and cost-effective architectures on AWS. This certification showcases my in-depth knowledge of AWS services, architectural best practices, and the ability to align solutions with business requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By achieving this certification, I have proven my capability to design cloud architectures that can handle varying workloads, ensure high availability, and recover from failures. I have also acquired the skills to optimize application performance, implement robust security measures, and control costs effectively using AWS services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this certification, I am equipped to deliver cloud solutions that meet the evolving demands of businesses and help them leverage the power of AWS to drive innovation and growth. I am committed to staying updated with the latest industry practices and maintaining the highest standards of excellence in cloud architecture design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am excited to apply my knowledge and expertise as an AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate to help organizations achieve their goals by harnessing the full potential of AWS. I look forward to contributing to the success of projects, collaborating with cross-functional teams, and architecting reliable and scalable solutions in the AWS cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to explore my website to learn more about my AWS certification and how I can assist you in architecting robust and efficient cloud solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
