<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Mohibul Alam</title>
    <link>https://mohibul75.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mohibul75.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mohibul75.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://mohibul75.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abra</title>
      <link>https://mohibul75.github.io/project/abra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mohibul75.github.io/project/abra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abra is an IoT project that offers comprehensive home insurance against burglary, fire, and water damage. With smart sensors and surveillance cameras, homeowners can monitor their property 24/7 and receive instant alerts through a mobile app. Abra&amp;rsquo;s automated response system allows for quick action to mitigate damage and contact relevant authorities. The user-friendly interface makes it easy to manage insurance policy, track incidents, and submit claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Responsibility:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented infrastructure on AWS serverless architecture using best practices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used Infrastructure as Code (IAC) approach with Terraform to automate infrastructure provisioning and management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provisioned various AWS services such as Lambda, SQS, EventBridge, IAM, CloudWatch, CloudFront, S3, Cognito, DynamoDB, SNS, and SES to ensure scalability, high availability, and cost optimization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed a comprehensive CI/CD pipeline using GitLab CI/CD, allowing for automated testing, continuous integration, and deployment of changes to production in a secure and efficient manner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Task Station</title>
      <link>https://mohibul75.github.io/project/external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mohibul75.github.io/project/external-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Task Station 23 by Brain Station 23 is a powerful tool that simplifies daily stand-ups for employees. With seamless integrations with popular project management tools such as Jira, Teams, ERP, Azure DevOps, and Trello, it allows for efficient tracking of project information, tasks, and time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Responsibility:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed scalable and resilient AWS Cloud Services architecture for application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilized Terraform for Infrastructure as Code (IAC) to automate infrastructure deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provisioned AWS services including S3, CloudFront, VPC, EC2, Load Balancer, Route53, and Certificate Manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented robust CI/CD pipeline using AWS Code Pipeline for automated build, test, and deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensured high code quality and reliability throughout the project lifecycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sykehuspartner</title>
      <link>https://mohibul75.github.io/project/sykeuspartner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mohibul75.github.io/project/sykeuspartner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sykehuspartner is a cutting-edge mobile application designed to simplify device tracking and allocation within hospitals. It streamlines the process of assigning digital devices to staff based on their shifts, ensuring efficient resource utilization and reducing administrative burden. This innovative solution enhances device availability, accountability, and operational efficiency in healthcare settings. Sykehuspartner is the answer to optimizing hospital device management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsibilities: Backend Infrastructure Management in Azure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
In my role as the Backend Infrastructure Manager for the Sykehuspartner project, I took on several key responsibilities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Azure Infrastructure Provisioning:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provisioned and maintained the Azure infrastructure, including the App Service and Container Service, ensuring optimal performance, scalability, and security for the backend services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CI/CD Pipeline Implementation:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed and implemented a robust Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) pipeline using GitHub Actions. This pipeline automated the build and deployment processes, allowing for efficient updates of the Docker image on the Azure App Service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Image Management:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed the creation and maintenance of Docker images, ensuring they were compatible with the Azure App Service Container Service. This involved optimizing container configurations for seamless deployment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code Quality Assurance with SonarQube:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilized SonarQube for code quality analysis and review. I set up SonarQube on an Azure Virtual Machine (VM), enabling continuous code inspection and improvement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Azure AD Management:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) configurations, including access control and app registration. I ensured that the right individuals or services had appropriate access permissions while maintaining security standards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security and Compliance:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented security best practices to safeguard the backend infrastructure and data. This included monitoring and addressing potential vulnerabilities and ensuring compliance with healthcare data regulations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation and Knowledge Sharing:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintained comprehensive documentation of the Azure infrastructure setup, configurations, and procedures. I also collaborated with the project team to share knowledge regarding Azure AD, CI/CD pipeline, and SonarQube integration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My role played a critical part in ensuring a stable, secure, and efficient backend infrastructure for Sykehuspartner. By orchestrating Azure services, implementing CI/CD pipelines, and overseeing code quality through SonarQube, I contributed to the project&amp;rsquo;s success in optimizing hospital device management.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wilhelmsen Platfrom 13</title>
      <link>https://mohibul75.github.io/project/wilhelmsen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mohibul75.github.io/project/wilhelmsen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wilhelmsen Platform 13 is a next-generation port management solution designed to transform the way port administrations operate. This innovative application offers a comprehensive suite of tools for managing vessel calls, coordinating port activities, integrating suppliers, and harnessing data-driven insights. By simplifying complex operations and fostering collaboration, it empowers port authorities to optimize efficiency, increase transparency, and elevate performance in the maritime industry. Wilhelmsen Platform 13 is the future of streamlined and effective port administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Responsibility:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsibilities: Project Infrastructure Maintenance in Azure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the project&amp;rsquo;s Infrastructure Specialist responsible for maintaining the Azure environment, I played a crucial role in ensuring the reliability, scalability, and efficiency of the infrastructure supporting the Wilhelmsen Platform 13 project. Here are my key responsibilities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Azure Infrastructure Management:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed and monitored all Azure resources, including virtual machines, databases, and networking components, to ensure optimal performance and cost-effectiveness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up and maintained Azure Resource Groups, Resource Policies, and Resource Locks to organize and secure resources effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django Backend Deployment:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deployed the Django backend application in Azure Container Instances (ACI) container group to enable containerized, scalable, and isolated execution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configured container instances with appropriate resource limits, networking, and scaling options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CI/CD Pipeline for Backend:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Established a Continuous Integration (CI) pipeline for the backend, automating the build and packaging of Docker images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated Azure Container Registry (ACR) to store Docker images and version control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented Continuous Deployment (CD) pipeline for seamless deployment of new backend versions to Azure Container Instances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vue Frontend Deployment:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deployed the Vue.js frontend application using Azure App Service Static Web Apps for a serverless and scalable web hosting solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configured custom domains, SSL certificates, and CDN integration for optimal frontend performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serverless Function and Service Bus Queue:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provisioned serverless resources and functions using Azure Functions to handle specific tasks within the application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up Service Bus Queues to enable asynchronous communication and message processing between different components.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Infrastructure as Code with Terraform:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilized Terraform to define, provision, and manage Azure resources in a repeatable and version-controlled manner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensured infrastructure changes were applied consistently across environments using Terraform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CI/CD for Infrastructure:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Established CI/CD pipelines for infrastructure changes using tools like Azure DevOps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensured that updates to infrastructure were tested and deployed automatically to maintain reliability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitoring and Scaling:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented monitoring and alerting solutions in Azure to proactively identify and respond to infrastructure issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensured the infrastructure could scale dynamically to handle varying workloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security and Compliance:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented security best practices, including Azure Key Vault for secrets management and Azure Security Center for threat detection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensured compliance with industry standards and regulations relevant to the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation and Knowledge Sharing:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintained detailed documentation of the Azure infrastructure setup, configurations, and procedures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborated with the project team to share knowledge and best practices related to Azure infrastructure management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My role was pivotal in ensuring the project&amp;rsquo;s success by providing a robust, efficient, and well-maintained Azure infrastructure to support the Wilhelmsen Platform 13 application and its CI/CD pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
