<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aws | Mohibul Alam</title>
    <link>https://mohibul75.github.io/tag/aws/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mohibul75.github.io/tag/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>aws</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mohibul75.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>aws</title>
      <link>https://mohibul75.github.io/tag/aws/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cracking the AWS Certified Solution Architect — Associate Exam</title>
      <link>https://mohibul75.github.io/post/aws-saa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mohibul75.github.io/post/aws-saa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mohibulalam75.medium.com/cracking-the-aws-certified-solution-architect-associate-exam-my-journey-and-tips-ad89eb3e637b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read this post on Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you preparing for the AWS Certified Solution Architect - Associate exam? Look no further! In this captivating blog post, I will share my personal experience and valuable insights that will help you ace the exam with flying colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📅 Exam Date: 22nd May 2023
🎓 Comprehensive Course: acloudguru&amp;rsquo;s AWS SAAC-03 (Updated)
I meticulously followed acloudguru&amp;rsquo;s AWS SAAC-03 course, leaving no stone unturned. This course provided me with a solid foundation, but I knew I needed more to succeed. So, I sought out the actual exam questions to sharpen my skills and boost my confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💪 Strengthening My Knowledge:  Examtopics Questions
To gain an edge, I dedicated myself to solving 300 real exam questions from Examtopics. This rigorous exercise not only reinforced my understanding but also prepared me for any surprises on the actual exam. Whenever I encountered unfamiliar terms not covered by acloudguru, I delved into AWS official documentation to ensure a comprehensive grasp of the subject matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📚 Beyond the Dump: The Real Path to Success
Beware of relying only on question dumps! It&amp;rsquo;s a recipe for failure. Many online resources mislead candidates into thinking that all the questions will come from the dumps. Trust me, that&amp;rsquo;s far from the truth. To triumph, you must first cover the entire syllabus and develop a clear understanding of all the services outlined in the official syllabus. Platforms like Udemy, acloudguru, or others can guide you on this learning journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💰 Exam Registration: Overcoming Payment Challenges
Registering for the exam can be a hassle, especially if you encounter payment issues with a dual currency card. Fear not! I have the perfect solution. I purchased a voucher worth 155.67 USD from xVoucher, allowing me to register hassle-free. If you&amp;rsquo;re registering from Bangladesh, you might face similar challenges, but with my tried-and-tested process, you&amp;rsquo;ll breeze through the registration process without a hitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🌩️ Embrace the Cloud, Get Certified, and Shine!
Embark on your AWS certification journey with confidence. By preparing diligently and following my guidance, you&amp;rsquo;ll be ready to conquer the exam and emerge victorious. Remember, success lies in mastering the syllabus and understanding the core services. Happy cloud computing!
Wishing you a day filled with exciting possibilities and boundless achievements. Good luck on your AWS certification journey!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
